

45 N Orchard St, Madison, WI, 53715, United States of America

□ (+1) 608-770-1154 | ► hyecheol.jang@wisc.edu | □ hyecheol123 (GitHub) | □ jhyecheol (LinkedIn)

Summary ____

Interested in finding optimized solution using Cloud (MS Azure) and writing understandable codes. Passionate about new technologies/languages/solutions. Experienced in **backend**/frontend development, deployment/operation, and **project management**. Open to **full-time** opportunities as a **software developer** or **solution architect**. Expect to graduate in May, 2023.

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Madison, WI, United States

Jul. 2018 - Current

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE; DOUBLE MAJOR IN STATISTICS; MINOR IN ENTREPRENEURSHIP

- **GPA: 3.89/4.00** | Dean's List: Fa18, Sp19, Sp20
- · Library Technology Student Assistant at College Library, Memorial Library, and CALS Computing Lab

Work Experience

Korean-American Scientists and Engineers Association - Wisconsin Chapter

Madison, WI, United States

DIRECTOR OF TECHNOLOGY (VOLUNTEER)

Dec. 2018 - Current

- Developed/Maintained NPO Chapter website and other useful IT tools for chapter management; responsible for various marketing, network activities, leadership board, and decision making.
- Project Manager & Back-End Developer for KSEA-Wisconsin Event Ticket System Project (Aug. 2022 Current)
 Building automated event ticket generation / admission service | Est. Release: Nov. 2022
 Send QR code with ticket information to the customers, check ticket validity and todos during admission with officers' mobile device
 Using Azure Function, Azure Blob Storage (for static website hosting), Azure Cosmos DB, CloudFlare (CDN) to minimize bandwidth, React Native
- Project Manager & Developer for KSEA-Wisconsin Website Rebuilding Project (Sep. 2019 Nov. 2019)
 Built website for NPO Chapter | Led project, Collaborated with five developers | Used HTML, CSS, Jekyll, Git, Jira, MS Teams, Adobe XD
 Divided tasks for collaboration accordingly | Provided training resources and counter errors and problems during the development process
 Successfully minimized operation budget GitHub Pages to host; used CloudFlare (CDN) to minimize bandwidth
 V2 project now launched (Est. Release: Dec. 2022) Add admin portal, elegant design, Next.JS-powered website; Serve on MS Azure

uniQon Seoul, Sc

TECHNICAL LEAD

Seoul, South Korea

Apr. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- · Used NodeJS (TypeScript) and MongoDB to develop and operate API server, web page, and admin portal
- Elaborated idea and developed products that provide "real" college application data and mentor information to prospective applicants with their high school information, keywords from extracurricular activities, and target school lists and majors
- Closely collaborated with CEO to build concrete business plans | Trained Interns/Software Developers and engage in HR tasks
- · Implemented IT infrastructure and remote working environment with Microsoft Teams, Jira, and GitHub
- Adopt Agile development workflow (Scrum) with weekly feedback to team/individuals | Traveled frequently for business meetings and recruiting

Republic of Korea Army

Busan, South Korea

Oct. 2020 - Jul. 2022

· Served at Wonkwang Nursing Home (Long-Term Care Facilities) to complete mendatory military duty of South Korea

Projects

BusanDevelopers Event Calendar

PROJECT MANAGER & DEVELOPER

SOCIAL SERVICE AGENT (SOCIAL WELFARE)

Busan, South Korea

Aug. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• Successfully built web event calendar for devleopers community | Led project, Collaborated with one back-end developer and one front-end developer

- Used React (MUI), NodeJS, Azure Cosmos DB, ExpressJS, and ReDoc | Manually set TypeScript React environment using ESLint, WebPack, and Babel
- · Effectively divided the project into smaller milestones, manage teammates' performance, and conduct weekly meetings
- Source Code: github.com/BusanDevelopers/BGM-Event-Calendar-API, github.com/BusanDevelopers/BGM-Event-Calendar-Webpage

CloudFlare Public Dynamic IP Update Script

Madison, WI, United States

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Built a script to update server's dynamic ip address to CloudFlare (DDNS) | Used Bash Shell Script | 50+ GitHub Star
- Source Code: github.com/hyecheol123/Cloudflare-Public-Dynamic-IP-Update

Honors & Awards

2022 Al·Blockchain Idea Pitching Competition

Busan, South Korea

3RD PLACE AWARD

Aug. 2022

Presentation: Bird Strike Prevention Methods at Gadeokdo New Airport Using Big Data and Machine Learning

Skills

DEVELOPER

Programming Language: TypeScript, Java, SQL, R, C, Python, Bash

Cloud Service: Microsoft Azure AZ-900, AI-900, DP-900 Certified, Naver Cloud Platform, AWS, DigitalOcean (and VPS providers)

DB: Azure SQL, Azure Cosmos DB, mariaDB, mongoDB, redis

Misc: Linux/UNIX Server (Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS), Git, CloudFlare, React Redux, MUI (React Library), HTML, CSS, Arduino, Raspberry Pi

Language: English (Advanced), Korean (Native)